# Vladimir Rodriguez

Architect, Full Stack engineer

I am extremely passionate about technology and solving new challenges, and I've been working as a solutions architect and developer for more than 8 years, using different technologies to implement microservices and monolithic solutions. At the beginning of my career I worked with languages like C++ and java (spring) but after a while I focused basically on java (spring) and PHP (Symfony) and javascript (react) with redux. My favorite hat is problem-solving skills. I consider myself a leader with collaborative energy and an excellent communicator and a proven record of delivering on time under pressure.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **TMX** Intermodal, Linden, NJ — *Architect* – *developer*

03 2020 - PRESENT

Solution to create a customer service platform with the capabilities to answer all their requirements including quotes, cargo tracking, etc.

Also maintain the CRM to support the sales team

Main tasks executed in the project:

Design the optimal architecture for the solution.

- React
- Redux
- Php (symfony)
- Java (spring)
- Mysql
- AWS

# **Schoolify**, San Francisco, CA — Architect – developer

07 2019 - 06 2020

Solution to create an e-learning platform with the capabilities to create video chat classes and share content in real time.

Main tasks executed in the project:

Design the optimal architecture for the solution.

210 Washington Ave Brooklyn, NY 11205 (917) -3614855 vladimirodriguez@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

Architect

Microservices

Monolithic

Design documents

Performance

Databases

Programming

PHP (Symfony).

Java (spring)

React.

Redux.

GraphQL.

**Database** 

Mysql

Postgres

Mongo

Elastic Search

**DevOps** 

**AWS** 

Docker

Continuous integration

**Tenkins** 

Nginx, apache, IIS

Soft Skills

Effective communication

Team work

Creativity

**Critical Thinking** 

Empathy

**LANGUAGES** 

- React
- Redux
- Php (symfony)
- Node
- Mysql
- Google cloud

# **Crestron**, Hollywood, FL — Architect – developer

10 2019 - 10 2020

Solution to create an application to handle the control a yacht resources (lights, shades, media, sound).

Main tasks executed in the project:

Design the optimal architecture for the solution.

- React
- Redux
- Php (symfony)
- C++

# **ALKANZA.US**, San Francisco, CA — Architect – developer

01 2015 - 09 2019

Create a solution that in an intuitive way gives the end user advice about his/her financial plans and actually implement them through brokers around the world.

Main tasks executed in the project:

Design the optimal architecture for the solution.

Implement the back end components in Python and Node and Golang.

Implement the front end components in React (react).

Design, implement and maintain the database in postgresql, mongo.

- Java (spring)
- Node
- React (redux)
- Postgresql
- Mongo
- Elastic search
- Docker

English, Spanish

# Resultado Total, Bogotá, Colombia — Architect – developer

11 2013 - 12 2015

#### Openbravo

Openbravo's personalization (ERP) IOS and Android app's implementation to show all the information regarding a sales module. Integration with different kind of services, restful and SOAP

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Implement the design.
- Create SOAP services in java.
- Create RESTFUL services
- Create Android application
- Create IOS application

#### Major contribution:

 I designed and implemented the whole solution, to be the most reliable and fastest avoiding overload in the server and providing an intuitive and user oriented interface.

Technologies: Openbravo, java, android, ios, postgresql, Python.

#### **Information System**

Create an information system that organizes all the shipping in a courier company.

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Implement the back end components in ruby on rails.
- Back end components in Golang.
- Implement the front end components in angularis.
- Design, implement and maintain the database in postgresql.

# Major contribution:

 I designed and implemented the whole solution, to be the most reliable and fastest avoiding overload in the server and providing an intuitive and user oriented interfaz.

Technologies: php (symfony), angularjs, postgres, redis.

CRM Microsoft Dynamics's personalization of .net, new additions to the sales module.

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Implemented the new components in C#

#### Major contribution:

• I implemented the solutions as fast as I could making the major amount of components as reusable as possible.

Technologies: C#, MsSql.

### **Information System**

Create an information system solution that manages the qualifications of the candidates for a job according to certain parameters.

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Implement the back end components in php and laravel.
- Components in Node.
- Implement the front end components in php.
- Design, implement and maintain the database in mysql.

#### Major contribution:

 I designed and implemented the whole solution, to be the most reliable and fastest avoiding overload in the server and providing an intuitive and user oriented interfaz.

Technologies: Node, mysql. Php (symfony)

# **NoMoreCards**, Los Angeles, CA — Architect – developer

07 2011 - 11 2013

No More Cards, Inc. is the developer of a revolutionary Omni-Channel commerce and promotion platform aimed at the needs of all sides of the transaction process. Our approach was simple, what was needed to create a mobile system that could truly deliver on all the promises and expectations of not just consumers, but merchants, processors, and the involved financial institutions as well

Project: Secure Payment System (july 2011 – november 2013)

Create an information system solution that secure credit cards and protect them from fraud.

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Coordinated with a team help to implement the back end in java.
- Coordinated with a team help to implement the back end in jsf.
- Design, implement and maintain the database in oracle.

- Coordinated with a team help to implement the mobile application with xamarin
- Coordinated with the team to help implement the DataPhone module, including the DataPhone programming.

#### Major contribution:

• Merge different technologies and lead the team to accomplish the task.

Technologies: Java (spring, hibernate, jsf), C#, oracle, xamarin

# **ASF**, Miami, FL — Architect – developer

03 2010 - 07 2011

Create an information system solution that manages the qualifications of the candidates for a job according to certain parameters.

Main tasks executed in the project:

- Design the optimal architecture for the solution.
- Implement the desktop application in C++.
- Implement the transactional module to trade with the brokers.
- Design, implement and maintain the database in mysql.

#### Major contribution:

 Make transactions with the NYSE in real time and implement the algorithms to process those transactions.

Technologies: C++, mysql

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Universidad de Los Andes**, Bogotá, Colombia — Bachelor of Engineering

During my years in university I focused mainly on algorithms and network communications.